## Dennis Nderitu Kinyanjui Tel: 0704640857

Email: devnderitu@gmail.com

#### **Education and Professional Qualifications**

- 1. **2016 2020** BSc in Business Information Technology from the Multimedia University of Kenya.
- 2. 2010 2013 Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education, Domus Marie School.

#### **Career Profile**

I'm a Business and Information Technology graduate, with knowledge of web development.

### **Key Professional Skills**

- 1. Intermediate Knowledge of HTML, CSS, Javascript
- 2. Photography.
- 3. Video-editing.
- 4. Programming In python and python frameworks(Django and Flask).
- 5. Project Management.
- 6. Excellent analytical, interpersonal, communication, and advocacy skills.

#### **Software Development Content Creator on You Tube**

 $Youtube\ Channel\ :::\ \underline{https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCnpO7lJTut87Klrd2mHI3fQ}$ 

My ALX Experience ::: https://youtu.be/twwt4a3ZBhQ

#### **Professional Experience**

<u>Sept 2016 - December 2020: Team Leader, Google Developer Groups,</u> Multimedia University Chapter. Nairobi, Kenya.

- Team Developer and tutor.
- -Aided in teaching other varsity students on how to program and follow international standards in software development.
- -Aided in planning and conducting campus-based events:-

Google cloud study jam 2019, Developer student Club web app Bootcamp 2018

# <u>Sep. 2017 – Mar. 2018: Team Member, Hult Prize Global Competition, Campus-Based. Nairobi, Kenya.</u>

- Brainstormed, developed, and implemented a project that was centred on impacting the lives of at least 10,000 people in the next 5 years.

-I worked with a team of four people and developed a project called Mfereji power was about harnessing power from wastewater pipes, streams, and rivers and use it to generate electricity for slum dwellers. We ideated and conceptualised the idea and pitched the mfereji power concept to a panel of judges on campus.

-My team was the first runner-up on the campus among fourteen groups in the university fraternity.

## <u>Feb. 2017 – May. 2017: Intern, Faidika Technologies. Nairobi, Kenya</u>

Faidika Technologies is a Technology Consulting Company that provides Product Management, IT Solutions, and Cloud Solutions to Small Medium Enterprises, Startups and Companies.

- In the Company, I was guided in web development best practices.
- Worked on a Social Network app using the Python and the flask framework.
- Interning there, gave me an edge in problem solving as I went back to campus, I had an easy time solving programming problems and also class projects.
- During the Internship, I was able to develop a pragmatic way in understanding the functionality of web applications.

## April. 2019 – August 2019: Threeways limited, Nairobi

Threeways limited was founded in 2015 when the team of two software engineers and one graphic designer met at the iHub. The team recognized the need of offering end-to-end solutions to the problems involved in the development of modern software applications and mobile apps. It's to that end that the company was formed. The company offers services in software development, data engineering, cloud deployment and graphic design.

During the Internship, I learned project management skills and how to use project management tools.

Took part in the development of project backend:- Implementation of telemetry parser for a sensor, for an IoT project. The implementation was done in python. Managing project demo dashboard;- this was a project based on an IoT project.

- Learned How to decode problem statements and break them down into modules.
- Learned how to execute project concept:-implementation of MVP- minimum viable product.
- Learned how to communicate project ideas and seek feedback.
- Learned how to be accountable for tasks done
- Developed and offered advice on presentations and meetings.

This Internship immersed me into the tech space and put me on the path of becoming a competent software engineer.

This experience has made me aware of what future employers need in terms of hard skills and soft skills on the job.

*Hard Skills*:- problem-solving skills:- How to break down a problem and articulate a solution. Programming skills:-proficiency in programming languages and frameworks. On the job, the most popular programming language in python and the knowledge of it puts a competitive edge on a person seeking a job opportunity.

Knowledge of Frameworks, especially web frameworks, is a requirement in the job-searching process. In this case, the framework used for the web was Django, a python web framework, which gives a software developer the ability to build web applications for potential clients.

This Experience has enabled me to have the ability to specialize in what I'm professionally good at. In this case, from the exposure and skills I have obtained from this experience, I have learned how to plan my work, in this case: projects, and execute them and develop a minimum viable product so as to show a proof of concept. With this, I can comfortably build applications and business solutions and use them to apply for future jobs and showcase my skills.

## <u>May. 2020 – September 2020: Employee, Soft Search Limited.</u> <u>Nairobi, Kenya</u>

- At Softsearch, I worked in a team that developed the soft search website. The website was implemented using javascript and styled-components.
- Also developed websites in WordPress for company clients.
- I was also assigned a digital marketing role, and shared knowledge on how to best use platforms such as Twitter, Instagram, and facebook.

## <u>August 2021 - January 2022: Intern, AMREF.</u> <u>Nairobi, Kenya</u>

I Joined Amref as an intern and was assigned to the Amref institute of capacity development, e campus department. I had the role of managing the Jibu E-learning Platform queries and issues through a customer service bot, as well as providing feedback to the organization on the User Experience of the Jibu e-learning platform. During my time there, I was able to report on queries and feedback on the jibu platform, advice the e campus team on what the

user wants based on feedback and queries, and offered real time communication and information to users through the bot to the users.

## <u>July 2021 - Present : Basketball Reporter, Woopy Sport</u> <u>Nairobi, Kenva</u>

Woopy sport is a Media Startup that has the objective of covering basketball in the country. In the past 7 months, I was part of covering 3 Basketball Leagues in Nairobi: 2 playoff tournaments for the Kenya Basketball Federation and Street League Africa regular season games. My role in woopy sport is to conduct interviews on players and Coaches, collect data on players, create news on players and the teams, record and edit videos, manage woopy sport social media, and also provide an analysis and report on the games played.

## Here is a sample of what i've done in woopy sport:

Woopy Sport Channel ::::

https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCPHYnFS2PkXmjsmgaUIHjpw

Woopy Sport Retro Channel :::

https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCXQNGUJYYHR FFUKvu5kmRA

Nderitu Basketball Radio :::

https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCeW1B55Z ff10IIJMMPCvjA

Ulinzi Eliminate Lakeside To move on to the Next Round

https://www.instagram.com/reel/CZZi6DOI0PE/?utm\_source=ig\_web\_copy\_link

https://www.instagram.com/reel/CZZjNHkoVeN/?utm\_source=ig\_web\_copy\_link

Sunday Basketball Recap::::: Div 1 & Premiere BBALL

https://www.instagram.com/tv/CZ\_vP7Fc7N/?utm\_source=ig\_web\_copv\_link

Saturday Basketball Recap::: Div 1 & Div 2 BBall,

https://www.instagram.com/tv/CZ-BrctFrzC/?utm\_source=ig\_web\_copy\_link

RECAP: Lumiz Take Down Dengueens

https://www.instagram.com/reel/CZMfsErl1IE/?utm\_source=ig\_web\_copy\_link

Nderitu's Desk ::::: A recap on Playoff Basketball -

https://www.instagram.com/tv/CaHcFwygHrF/?utm\_source=ig\_web\_copy\_link

Ulinzi Warriors vs KPA Finals Matchup -

https://www.instagram.com/tv/CaHctgzLEbM/?utm\_source=ig\_web\_copy\_link

Coach David Post Game Interview | KBF PLAYOFFS - https://youtu.be/QbCNBmyDLuc

Dan Mbugua PG NBK Post Game Interview - <a href="https://youtu.be/PruyYkvjvgc">https://youtu.be/PruyYkvjvgc</a>

Youtube Channel ::: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCnpO7lJTut87Klrd2mHI3fQ

My ALX Experience ::: <a href="https://youtu.be/twwt4a3ZBhQ">https://youtu.be/twwt4a3ZBhQ</a>

## **Personal Attributes**

- 1. Hardworking
- 2. Trustworthy
- 3. Honest

## **Referees**

## Raphael Muia

Amref Institute of Capacity Development (ICD) raphael.muia@amref.org

Phone: 0712051913

## **Morris Mwaura**

Three ways technologies morris@3ways.co.ke

## James Mwai

Skygarden smartemwa@gmail.com